blog.jimdo.com 2015-12-30

# Privacy Statement - Jimdo

At Jimdo, we place the highest importance on handling your personal data with respect and confidentiality. Accordingly, Jimdo adheres to all applicable data protection laws and regulations, in particular to the strict [German Federal Data Protection Act](http://www.bfdi.bund.de/EN/DataProtectionActs/DataProtectionActs_node.html/). The following Privacy Policy outlines which data is collected from you and how it is handled. This policy applies to all Jimdo products and services. Jimdo is a service of Jimdo GmbH. 

For questions about this privacy policy, you can write to us at any time via [our contact form](http://www.jimdo.com/info/privacy-contact/) or by mail: 

**Jimdo GmbH**

ATTN: Privacy 

Stresemannstraße 375 

22761 Hamburg 

Germany 

Jimdo collects, processes, and uses your personal information without asking for explicit consent only when this information is necessary for fulfilling the terms of our contract and for billing purposes. 

What does this mean for you? 

**Information you provide**

When registering a Jimdo website, it is necessary to specify a username and an email address. The specified username will be made public as part of the web address **username.jimdo.com**. The email address is used to send you notifications concerning your Jimdo website. These include your login data, announcements, product-related information, and more. You always have the option to unsubscribe from our newsletter and individual email alerts (email notification of new contact form entries, comments, or guestbook posts). For certain service packages, such as JimdoPro/JimdoBusiness and/or certain features, such as the web store, other contact and payment details are required. This data will be stored only until you delete your Jimdo account. There is one exception to the above provision: for legal reasons we are required to retain billing information from JimdoPro/JimdoBusiness customers for seven years. 

**Information on the usage of your Jimdo website**

When you log into your Jimdo website, the Jimdo server automatically collects data on how you use Jimdo in what is known as an activity log. The server collects information on your activity (including storage space used, number of sign-ins, etc.), statistical data (such as your browser, date and time of log in, cookie ID, and referrer URL), and your IP address. 

**Storage of cookies on your computer**

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer. Most frequently, cookies are stored for the duration of the current session, i.e. until you close your browser, but in some cases they are stored longer than this. Jimdo uses cookies as follows: 

**Session cookies for identification**

When you sign into your Jimdo website, Jimdo automatically sets a cookie to recognize your browser (this is called a session cookie). This allows you to enter your password only once per session (when you log in), without being asked repeatedly to do so while editing your Jimdo website. Most browsers accept cookies by default, but it is possible to change your browser settings to refuse all cookies. If your browser is set to refuse all cookies, Jimdo will not function properly. You can delete cookies at any time, however, but will have to sign in again the next time you want to edit your Jimdo site. 

**Advertising and analytics cookies**

Third-party services are used on Jimdo.com and your Jimdo website for advertising and analysis-related purposes. These services may set third-party cookies and/or pixel tags (web beacons), in order to be able to display specific regional or topic-targeted banners to you while you surf the web. Most browsers allow you to deactivate third-party cookies in their settings. Please note however, that this may affect the functionality of other sites outside Jimdo (forums, etc.). You can also choose to deactivate third-party cookies by going to the [Network Advertising Initiative site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and following the instructions there. 

Jimdo uses the following third-party services: 

**Jimdo.com uses Google Analytics** , a web analysis service of Google Inc., (“Google”). Google Analytics stores cookies on your computer which allow you to analyze the surfing patterns of visitors to your website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be sent to a Google server in the United States and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators and to report other website activity and internet-related services. If required by law, Google will pass along this information to third parties. Google will also pass along data to third parties for processing, provided this processing is done on behalf of Google. Under no circumstances shall Google connect your IP address with any other data held by Google. If you wish, you can adjust your browser settings so as to refuse cookies. Please keep in mind, however, that if you refuse all cookies, you will not necessarily have access to all functions of this website. By using this site, you consent to the processing of your data by Google as described above, for the aforementioned purpose. If you wish to prevent your IP address from being saved now and in the future, you can do so by installing a browser plug in [available here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en/). 

You can find additional information on how Google handles data related to your person in its advertising network here: [Advertising and Privacy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). 

**Jimdo’s Statistics feature** , powered by Google Analytics, uses the "Anonymize IP" option, which ensures that your IP is only processed in an anonymized form. 

**Facebook**. Our website uses social plugins (“plugins”) from facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook, Inc. (“Facebook”). These plugins are branded with a Facebook logo or with a phrase such as "Facebook Social Plugin". When you visit a page on our website containing a Facebook Social Plugin, your browser creates a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin is transmitted directly to your browser by Facebook and is then incorporated into the website. Facebook, in turn, is aware of every time the website is accessed. If you have a Facebook profile, the company is able to associate the website visit to your profile by using JavaScript and setting cookies. If you interact with plugins on a website, for example by clicking the “Like” button or replying to a message, this information will be sent directly to Facebook and stored there. With the right browser plug-in you can prevent this information from being transferred, but please keep in mind that Facebook Social Plugins will no longer work properly. 

For more information on the purpose and scope of data collection and further processing and use of data by Facebook, as well as your rights and changes to settings you can make, please review [the Facebook privacy policy here](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php/). 

**Log information**. When you visit a Jimdo website (jimdo.com, your own Jimdo site, or websites of other Jimdo users), the Jimdo server automatically saves the information that your browser sends whenever you visit this site. The information includes your request, IP address, browser type and language, and the date and time of your request. The information is used solely for analyzing and maintaining the technical operation of the servers and network as a whole. It is automatically deleted after three months. 

**The communication between you and Jimdo**. Should you have questions, you can contact us at any time via email or on jimdo.com. We save your message so as to reply as quickly as possible, and to track and improve our support service. Your information will only be used to process your request. 

**Newsletter**. Our newsletter contains links and graphics to help us learn whether you actually read our newsletter and which topics interest you most. This allows us to improve our service and increase quality control. 

###  Visibility and publicly accessible information 

**The Jimdo website**. Any information that you put on your Jimdo website can be viewed by other Internet users. Therefore, we ask that you be careful and responsible with any personal information (such as addresses and phone numbers) and confidential data (such as passwords and login details) you put on your website. Keep in mind that password-protected areas do not absolutely prevent unauthorized access: files uploaded on password-protected pages can still be accessed through direct links. 

**Administrative access to your Jimdo website**. Jimdo team members are authorized to access the administrative section (CMS) of your Jimdo website when fulfilling customer service requests and tracking errors. In such cases, they are able to view all parts of your JimdoPage, including all password-protected areas. All members of our team are regularly trained in privacy concerns and the confidentiality of data according to Article 5 of the German Federal Data Protection Act. 

Your information will never be sold to third parties. We will not disclose any personal data without your consent, unless: 

  * We are required by law to do so. 

  * We are obliged to do so to enforce our Terms of Use or the rights of Jimdo. 

  * We make use of third-party services to provide you with Jimdo products or services. In these cases, we may need to share information. For example:  

    * **Domain registration**. Both paid packages include at least one domain name. When you register a domain, Jimdo is required to transfer registration data to the relevant domain organization. For more information on the nature and extent of data transferred, please consult the authority responsible for your domain: 

> >     1. .com, .net, .org, .info, .biz domains (ICANN): <http://www.icann.org/en/udrp/udrp-policy-24oct99.htm>
>>     2. .eu domains (EURid): <http://www.eurid.eu/files/reg_pol_EN.pdf>
>>     3. .de domains (DENIC): <http://www.denic.de/de/bedingungen.html>
>>     4. .ch domains (SWITCH): <https://www.nic.ch/>
>>     5. .at domains (NIC.AT):<http://www.nic.at/service/rechtliche_informationen/registrierungsrichtlinien/>

Depending on the registrar, this transferred registration data may be made publicly visible online. In particular, personal registration information for .com, .net, .org, .info, and .biz domains will be made public on the WHOIS.com website. You should keep this in mind when registering one of these TLDs. 
    * **Email addresses**. When you set up an email account or forwarding address for your Jimdo website, we create an account for you with Rackspace Limited. Rackspace Limited assumes responsibility for the technical delivery and management of your emails. You can read [Rackspace’s privacy policy here](http://www.rackspace.com/information/legal/privacystatement.php/). 
    * **Newsletter, guestbook and contact form**. SendGrid, Inc., is responsible for all emails that are sent through your website (such as notifications about new guestbook posts or store orders). [SendGrid, Inc.’s privacy policy can be found here](http://sendgrid.com/privacy.html/). 
    * **Spam protection**. We use Akismet to scan incoming comments, messages in your contact form, and guestbook entries as a precautionary measure against spam. In order to do this, we transfer incoming messages to Akismet, where they are analyzed. Akismet is a service of Automattic, Inc. You can read [Automattic, Inc.’s privacy policy here](http://automattic.com/privacy/). 
    * **User content**. When you upload images or files to your Jimdo website, these files may be uploaded to the cloud services of Amazon S3 or Nirvanix. Amazon and Nirvanix’s privacy policies can be found here: 
    * **Statistics**. If you are a JimdoPro or JimdoBusiness user, we use Google Analytics to generate statistics for your website. Data collected is processed in a non-personally-identifying form (“anonymizeIp”). [Google Analytics’ privacy policy can be found here](http://www.google.com/analytics/privacyoverview.html/). 
    * **Content delivery**. We use CDNetworks Inc. to deliver the content of your JimdoPage. CDNetworks ensures that your website can be quickly accessed all over the world. [CDNetworks’ privacy policy can be found here](http://www.cdnetworks.com/privacy-statement/). 

If Jimdo is ever acquired by another company, user information could be transferred to the acquiring party. 

**Information**  
We are happy to give you a summary of all data we have collected from you (Article 34 of the German Federal Data Protection Act). This request for information is free of charge and will be processed as soon as it is received. Normally, we deliver such requests via email, but you can also request it be sent via snail mail. If you want a detailed breakdown of collected data, please let us know precisely which data you would like to learn about. We want to make sure that you are really you and not someone pretending to be you, so we will need a copy or scan of your passport or driver’s license to fulfill a request for information. We only use the scan or copy to check your ID and respond to your request. 

**Correction, deletion, or blocking**

In accordance with Article 35 of the German Federal Data Protection Act, you are entitled to request that any data we collect from you be corrected, deleted or blocked from further use in cases that fall under the terms of the article. 

If you do not consent to this privacy policy in whole or in part, now or at a later point in time, you will no longer be able to use our services. In this case, you are required to inform us immediately and to delete your JimdoFree site at once, and to cancel your JimdoPro or JimdoBusiness site if you have one. 

We may change our privacy policy from time to time. Your rights, however, will not be reduced without good reason. All changes to the privacy policy will be listed on this page. If the changes are significant, we will announce the change to users (in an email newsletter, for example). 

If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, you can [contact us here](http://www.jimdo.com/info/privacy-contact/) or by mail at: 

**Jimdo GmbH**

ATTN: Privacy 

Stresemannstraße 375 

22761 Hamburg 

Germany 

Revised October 20, 2011 

**Please note:** The previous versions of our privacy policy (from February 2007, May 2008 and February 2010) are located here: [Older Versions of the Jimdo privacy policy](http://www.jimdo.com/info/privacy-statement-old/)

If you choose not to accept the changes of our privacy policy, you have the opportunity to decline them within one month. After this period of time, the changes are considered to be accepted. Please enter your objection via the [contact form](http://www.jimdo.com/info/privacy-contact/) below or write to us at: 

**Jimdo GmbH**

Stresemannstrasse 375 

22761 Hamburg 

Germany
